because for long time since I first
published the donut diagram in 2012
people have been saying we're coming
come into that year we want to do that
the year weather here is the town a city
a nation on Twitter somebody sent me
this from Berlin we're asking what would
it mean for Berlin to become a doughnut
to see in Stockholm an urban designer
sent me this picture he said this is my
design table with opening a new suburb
of the city it's going to be in this
area here there's a train station that's
not been open for 30 years this is long
been planned to be a new suburb he said
I've got the donor on the design table
we want to make it the world's most
sustainable living history we're going
to call it a donut district and I
thought what some people are wanting to
use it so in fact here are is the core
vision and this is what I could talk
with your new venues we had a
breakthrough moment and this is a cool
philosophy more than 20% ambitious place
in the 21st century we need to be asking
themselves a fourfold question we want
to be thriving people in a thriving
place that's how their little vision but
we must do so well respecting the
well-being of all people in the whole
planet and that's how global
responsibility and everything now I'm
now going to show you is sitting
underneath this philosophical
foundations so it means a local question
and a global question a social question
in ecological so this four part question
what does it thriving mean to people
here and what does it mean for this
place to thrive how do we do that while
respecting the rights of all people and
how do I do
do that role respecting the health of
the whole planet I'm going to show you
briefly the methodologies to these need
for different methodologies to answer
the aim is to create what we thinking of
playfully calling a city selfie we're
thinking of a number of cities that's
working with c40 so to show a city
itself through these four lenses of its
ambition and weariness today has the
get into the journey to becoming
thriving place for its own space and the
world in which in this so on the love
I'm going to start the local question
what does thriving mean to people here
let the people of this place to find
what thriving means it will be very
different in different places citizens
of the world how they consider that to
be we wanted to be determined by the
local residents withdrawing tragic to a
quota for everything we're doing we want
to create a threshold level what is the
threshold and where are we now
so to get the threshold what targets has
this place set for itself already and
what can you see that stir now we took
the Doolin bomb which is the target tree
and Saddam has forty nine goals that it
set for itself is that what these year
already agreed targets but also one of
the people at this place think is a
decent level of health care education
transport housing lets people up facing
those and we want to draw on so this is
the imagines data don't quote any of
that I just made that up but we might
then find that 11 percent of children
living in compromise somebody mentioned
finding for children I think you missed
it yesterday
you son of them so we'll fill it in with
locally available data will add quotes
from people that bring lived experience
the data because data is really can be
lifeless until you actually hit what it
means to somebody to live in those
conditions and also we're going to be
using word clouds what I love about
living here is what's missing in this
place is and get work crab impressions
from the community anybody out there who
does come work what else should we be
doing how else should we be illustrating
and making visible what the people of
this place think it needs to thrive him
I love your ideas secondly and this is
the hard to Janine Benyus his work if
the city master damage where we've been
where he's best you know we want to be a
thriving place Jeanine would say well
what's the wildland next door it's
actually quite hard enough
they wouldn't ask the water so what
would the world landing but go to the
bar next door help the ecosystem of this
bio region of this habitat and take its
metrics and then these become the
metrics how much carbon dioxide is
sequestering how much water it's drawing
us is always forming how much
biodiversity is housing these become the
metrics for the city and an aim of the
city is to match or exceed nature's
performance it's wonderfully
outrageously ambitious and yet totally
natural common-sense that's what I love
about this idea so you go to the wild
land next door measuring its metrics in
all these ecological performance of how
nature is regenerating itself and these
become the metrics of the city and then
you meander where the city is this and
this is imaginary this is the shortfall
now what kind of design use could be put
into place in this place that would
store more water purify more air cool
the air stop erosion with sequester more
carbon for example I find it so exciting
as the design starting point for 21st
century place so we could then put those
two together this is all imaginary what
I'm showing you is the no real data you
can put these two together and say the
social goals were set by the people of
this place of what they think writing
means and we're probably falling short
and the ecological goals are set by the
world line next door and we are
currently falling short in our city now
we need to move aim to fill all of that
in to live up to those thresholds or
even exceed them many places could say
that's all that's better thank you we
now get to work
but that's only local emissions of
driving people driving place we have to
recognize the deep interconnectedness
replaced and so we also have to ask but
how do we do that
wonderful hi our mission here in
Rotterdam we all got our first people
that are eating our food well-dressed
whether the first come from where did
the food come from whether these clothes
come for what's the ecological
social impact of a living well here we
have to take account of that how do we
respect the well-being of all people and
the whole planet so let me start with
the ecological how can we quantify a
city's consumption footprint not just in
terms of greenhouse gases but in terms
of nitrogen and phosphorus in terms of
land use in terms of fresh water in
terms of ocean impact we are evolving
this right now and working with our
wonderful researcher called
Frederick Erickson who has is currently
taking if you're into this stuff taking
global footprint data scaling it to the
city
top-down first with population and
income size but then adding local
available data to refine it and give it